Front-end Web Developer

Ryan PINA-SILASSE NGAMI, 23

+33 6 16 07 40 54 — ryanpinas77@gmail.com — linkedin.com/in/ryan-pina-silasse — github.com/N95Ryan

Champs-sur-Marne, France

Front-end web developer with 2 years of experience. I have had the opportunity to work on various projects using technologies such as TypeScript, Next, and Go. My interest in new technologies and my ability to quickly adapt allow me to design modern and pleasant interfaces.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Go
Frontend: React, Next, Tailwind, Sass
Backend: Express.js, MySQL, GraphQL

Mobile:React Native, ExpoDeployment / Hosting:Vercel, Netlify, FirebaseTools:Git, Docker, Postman

Graphic Design: Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator

Project Management: Jira, SCRUM, Agile Methodology

Communication: French (native language), English (C1)

Professional Experience

Junior Frontend Web Developer

Konbini — Online Media — Paris, France

October 2022 - October 2024

- JavaScript, TypeScript, Next, GraphQL
- Redesign of the website pages to improve its overall aesthetic and user experience.
- UI optimization to enhance usability and accessibility, leading to increased user engagement.
- Management of external ad integration, thereby increasing ad revenue and the company's exposure.
- SEO adjustments and optimization leading to a significant improvement in search engine rankings.

Web Developer

April 2021 - August 2022

French Innov — Software Company — Stains, France

- JavaScript, Bootstrap
- Design and development of fully responsive websites to provide optimal UX on all devices.
- Integration of interactive features on order kiosks.

Education

Bachelor's Degree: Web and Mobile Development

HETIC, the Internet School — Montreuil, France

September 2022 - September 2024

Courses: Web Development, Object-Oriented Programming, 3D Design, Database Management, Project Management

Personal Projects

Bumble B - Connected Remote-Controlled Car -2024

Link: Bumble-B

Bumble B is a mobile application developed as part of my final year project. The app is used to control a small car equipped with an ESP32 module provided by the school. From the app, we can control its speed, direction, and also retrieve statistics.

Bitjustu - AI Image Editor — November 2023

Link: bijutsu.app

I created this project to practice integrating tokens into a front-end project. It is an interactive application that allows the user to edit an image via text lines. For this, I used the Replicate API.

 $\begin{tabular}{lll} \textbf{Tic-Tac-Toe - Interactive Game} & -- September 2023 \\ \end{tabular}$

Link: <u>tic-tac-toe.app</u>

This project is a web application developed to illustrate the fundamentals of JavaScript programming and DOM manipulation. The purpose of the application is to allow users to play Tic-Tac-Toe directly in their browser, while demonstrating state management and user interaction capabilities in JavaScript.

EcoMap - Interactive Map — July 2023

Link: figma.com/ecomap

This application mockup was created in collaboration with fellow students as part of our first-year final presentation. The app allows users to consult a list of ecology and environmental events around them via an integrated map. This project significantly improved my project management skills.

React Calculator — October 2022

Link: calculatrice-react.app

As its name suggests, this is a calculator made with React. The primary purpose of this project was to introduce myself to the framework, and secondarily to test my self-taught development skills. Being very autonomous, this was a relevant project for me.

Hobbies

- Practicing Judo: A discipline that has taught me perseverance, rigor, and respect.
- Interest in Cooking: A field that has allowed me to broaden my view of culinary traditions.
- Passion for Fashion: Allows me to express my creativity through my personal style.